Stephanie George

(732) 986 0036 | <u>stephanie.george22@gmail.com</u> | 78 Mercer Street, Metuchen, NJ 08840 <u>github.com/stephgeorge22</u> | <u>www.linkedin.com/in/stephgeorge22</u>/ | <u>stephgeorge22.github.io/Portfolio-/</u>

Summary

A Full Stack Engineer pivoting to building the digital world from the physical world (as a current Civil Engineer). With five years of professional experience and an Engineering degree, I am highly analytical, client/customer oriented and a true problem solver at heart. I'm excited to pursue my passion of building applications to improve the daily life of people while delivering an exceptional user-experience.

Skills

Full Stack Javascript | Node.js | jQuery | Express.js | SQL | MySQL | Sequelize | MongoDB | Object-Oriented Programming | Bootstrap | Materialize | RESTful API | MVC | GraphQL | Git | AutoCAD | ArcGIS | Heroku

Projects

ReciPlanner - Express, Node.js, Sequelize

This app was a 4 person team collaboration that allows users to add recipes and view others posted recipes. github.com/stephgeorge22/reciplanner | reciplanner.herokuapp.com/

Weather Dashboard - Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap

An app that gives you the current weather, five day forecast and utilizes local storage. github.com/stephgeorge22/weather-dashboard/ | stephgeorge22/weather-dashboard/ | stephgeorge2 | <a

Experience

Najarian Associates - Civil Engineer

Eatontown, NJ | May 2021 - Present

- Designed stormwater systems and geometric plans utilizing AutoCAD.
- Created design plans for NJ Department of Transportation permits.
- Worked with clients to get their design plans approved by Township Boards and into the construction phase.

WSP - Civil Engineer

Morristown, NJ | November 2019 - December 2020

- Designed flood gates, fish ladder, green infrastructure, roads and parking lots utilizing ArcGIS and AutoCAD.
- Managed workflow for indirect reports to complete 100% design plans, specifications reports and permits.
- Created project management plans, risk assessments, budgets, cost estimates and schedules.

HDR - Civil Engineer

New York City, NY | July 2018 - October 2019

- Developed multiple green infrastructure concepts utilizing ArcGIS for NYC Parks that received client buy-in.
- Designed roadway systems including storm sewer system, pavement striping, etc. utilizing AutoCAD.

Tetra Tech - Civil Engineer

New York City, NY | July 2016 - June 2018

- Analyzed 100+ flooding data points and created 35 projects, each with unique features.
- Created a tracking and monitoring plan to measure program success.

Education

Rutgers Coding Bootcamp | Full Stack Javascript Certificate: April 2021 - September 2021 Rutgers University | Bachelor of Science in Environmental Engineering: September 2011 - May 2016